We have to get things started in
Barcelona. La Liga champions will miss
on 54
goals. Robert Lewandowski, Ferran
Torres, Marcus Rashford have left the
club. Rodri is now a Barcelona player
after Barca [music] completed a transfer
fee with Manchester City for 77 [music]
million euros. Also, Joao Cancelo has
been now has landed in Barcelona, will
return to the club [music] after fixing
his deal in the Saudi league. But Rodri,
the question, the big question is so far
no traditional number nine. And Raphinha
seems to be the one who has played
several roles, different roles with
Barcelona under Hansi Flick. Is he the
one if if if there's no other
traditional number nine coming before
the transfer window closes, will he be
Barca's number nine?
>> Uh we have to wait and see what uh Flick
has in mind. But indeed, you got that
option. And I think that if you have to
choose in between Anthony Gordon, Lamine
Yamal, and Raphinha, indeed I would go
for Raphinha. First of all, because
Anthony Gordon can play on the left as
he proved in Newcastle. And I think that
he still has to prove a lot of things in
in Spain. Like he has to adapt as soon
as possible. But it could be his natural
position.
Lamine Yamal, he's in shape and he's
getting back in shape again after
uh the World Cup in in the US, Canada,
and Mexico and winning the trophy. And I
think he still has to be there for at
least one or maybe two seasons. And for
me, that's why Raphinha should be the
ideal false nine. Because he's quick, he
can play in between lines, he he has
experience. And indeed, he has the best
the best goal of those three up in
attack.
>> Let's not forget Shaq, two seasons ago
he was fully fit, played a full season,
and scored over 30 goals in all comps.
Does that make him the most reliable
source of goal scoring for Barca so far?
>> Without question. There was talk earlier
in the summer that Anthony Gordon could
play could fill in that that number nine
role.
Anthony Gordon is quick.
He's not the finisher that Raphinha is.
So [music] again, I'm I'm I'm going to
echo Rodri here. If you have a choice
between Anthony Gordon
>> [music]
>> and Raphinha to play as that number nine
and we freely assume that Lamine Yamal
will continue to operate on the right
hand side as as he always does as his
best position. Raphinha is easily the
better of of the two choices. Maybe if
you want um
>> [music]
>> tempted to say traditional, played my
football in England, but a bigger target
man to play through through the middle
as that number nine, Anthony Gordon can
fill in on occasion, but more times than
not against better opponents, I think
Raphinha will be the preferred choice.
>> Now,
transfer transfer window's still open.
>> Mhm.
>> Barcelona, they now have they they have
made serious business for Anthony
Gordon,
for Adeyemi, and now obviously Rodri. Is
there
still space available? Is there still
some budget available for Barcelona to
find a proper number nine? Because it
seems like the Julian Alvarez option is
no longer on the table for Barca.
>> Uh when you talk to Barca, they say,
"No, we are still going to try to try at
least try with with Julian Alvarez." And
yeah, and and I looked to them like
this, like, "Are you serious?"
>> Everybody's making that face. Everybody.
Everybody like,
"For real? How? HOW ARE YOU GOING TO DO
IT?"
>> YEAH, I mean, the thing is that they
tell you that they got budget enough.
But it is I mean, for me this is like a
game. It It looks like they have
unlimited budget to to sign whoever. But
the thing is that they have to face
Atletico Madrid and Atletico Madrid
doesn't really want to sell Julian
Alvarez and not even to Barcelona
because they would be reinforcing a
direct rival for any Spanish trophy. So,
I think it's going to be almost
impossible. I'm not going to say this is
impossible, but 99.9%
impossible [clears throat]
for Barcelona. First of all, because I
think this is going to be really,
really, really expensive. If there is
any last chance, because we remember
that Atletico Madrid refused, rejected a
Real Madrid offer around 150 million
euros, and I find this really hard to
equal for Barcelona. So, for me, it's
almost done this and and and thing is
that, you know, uh this morning I again
called Atletico Madrid, and they again
and again and again are saying the same
message. No, he's not in sale, and we're
not going to sell him to Barcelona.
>> It even feels like it's not a matter of
money. It's a matter of respect.
>> Uh it's it's Yeah, I I I which I I fully
agree with. Atletico Madrid, well, yes,
for all intents and purposes, they're
the third largest club in in Spanish
football. They
want to be seen differently.
Whether they see themselves differently
or not, they want to be seen
differently, and at the very least, they
want to be respected as that, and do not
want to be seen to be bullied over
players for whatever reason it may be.
So, I I I get him. I'm agreeing with
Roger here. This is not about money. We
could question Barcelona's ability to
pull
even more levers this summer.
But, Atletico Madrid have dug their
heels in, and I think this is not about
money. This is not about Julian
Alvarez's
supposed want to leave. This is about
them being respected. They felt
disrespected and will not back down from
that.
>> Now, Shak, let me stay with you here.
Hansi Flick has been extremely,
extremely smart the way he has managed
his squad.
>> Mhm.
>> But, it seems like Raphinha it's clearly
a leader
on the field, off the field, but also
his performance has been fantastic,
especially when he starts on that left
wing, as opposed to Lamine Yamal. If you
take him out of that spot just because
you have to fill the number nine
position, are you removing Raphinha from
the place that he's the most dangerous
at?
>> Yes, you are. Short answer to that
question, Mo. Um
Yeah, yes, you are. Raphinha for me is
at his best on that left-hand side uh
for Barcelona to provide balance to to
Lamine Yamal out on the right-hand side.
You have a finisher like you've had in
in Lewandowski last couple of seasons.
That's when I think you've seen the
[music] best of Barcelona. Now, given
any number of circumstances
they have to make do. I think they'll
have to make do with what they have in
the squad this season. Raphinha has
shown that he can play on that left, he
can play on the right, he can play
through the middle, he can sit in behind
and and play in that that hole as a 10
role
and be
just about as as effective in any one of
those positions. Now, you look at the
squad, you look at what options there
there there may be.
Um we've got a Dani Olmo, we've got a
Fermín López, uh we've got Rooney to
come in. You look at those or you look
at those. Olmo can play in the 10. The
others you want to feel are more squad
players and and and needed for rotation
in what may be a front three or front
four.
That means, as we discussed before, I
think Raphinha would be tasked with
playing as that number nine, the
goalscorer for or the goal-getter for
for Barça.
>> Can I ask you both a question?
>> Of course.
>> Because uh there was a part of the
transfer market where FC Barcelona
people, according to my sources, they
were debating inside the club
one option. That it was, okay, can we
sell Raphinha and get Julián Álvarez?
And that was an interesting debate
inside Barcelona because they were
thinking about this that Xavi was just
saying, which I find it really
interesting, but at the same time they
were saying like, yeah, who's going to
be better for us now to win the
Champions League trophy, which is now
the main target for Barcelona, Julian
Alvarez or Raphinha?
>> Production on the field
could be equal.
>> Mhm.
>> But I go back to what Raphinha means to
that dressing room.
>> Yeah.
>> His leadership skills. And it's not only
the way I see it, is the way Hansi Flick
has expressed it. Do you guys remember a
game last last season? Barcelona ended
up winning, but
Hansi Flick's body language was he was
devastated. The one player that
approached him to comfort him, it was
Raphinha. And Hansi Flick then explained
how well they work together and the
relationship that they have and the way
it works. I think Raphinha is crucial to
this Barcelona success, even though
Julian Alvarez is a fantastic player.
Now, the other option, because a lot of
people see a parallel between Lionel
Messi's career trajectory and Lamine
Yamal's. Messi also started also started
on the right wing and then transitioned
to a false nine spot where he became
world-class, historic.
Is it too soon to ask Lamine Yamal
to go and change positions and start
playing on a different role because from
what we hear from our insiders is that
he really wants to do that. He really
wants to become that false nine for
Barcelona.
>> I I I I say yes.
>> I I I I I
in that leave Lamine Yamal where he is.
Out on that right hand side where he
continues to be effective. I think as he
grows in the game, as he starts his
understanding gets better, his
um
kind of maturity and impact in the team
gets better. He will start to drift
inside naturally, as Lionel Messi did.
And then you figure you realize, okay,
now we have to figure out how we how we
kind of plug those gaps that Lamine
Yamal leaves when when when he drifts in
from from from that side. I'm I'm not
moving Lamine Yamal right now.
>> Yeah.
>> He'll move himself.
We'll figure out as a team how we how we
adapt to suit.
>> The one final thing I said about this
Rodri, let's see if you agree, is the
best club in the world right now, PSG.
>> Mhm.
>> They don't play with a set number
[snorts] nine. No, it's very fluid.
Spain,
the world champions, Oyarzabal is the
number nine, but is he a pure number
nine? He's not. So, why couldn't
Barcelona
try to follow that
and play with a traditional proper
number nine?
>> I understand, but first of all, you
don't have Luis Enrique, and secondly,
you don't [laughter] have Kvaratskhelia,
you don't have Dembélé, you don't I
mean, the powerful that they are at the
PSG in that attacking line is just
incredible. So, that's why I think PSG
are far far away above Barcelona in that
term.
>> I also think that the the two well,
international football and and well,
Ligue 1 for for PSG
are
shorter tournament formats. And in that,
international football with eight games
and you win a World Cup,
PSG
are going to win the league.
They barely play their starters in the
in the league, in all honesty. They are
judged on the Champions League. Again,
shorter format to what we're used to in
a league format where you're playing
anywhere between 36 and 40 games. I just
feel the ask is different in those
circumstances. And yes, there have been
successes. Barcelona has had very
successful seasons with a false nine.
Those are the anomalies.